

Kat Mountford





Junior Full Stack Engineer

Melbourne

0402 449 403

katricemountford@gmail.com



katmountford.com

ABOUT ME

Hey, I'm Kat, a Junior Software Engineer with 7+ years in tech, including 4 years as a Product Manager.

After pivoting from Product to Software Engineering, I've grown key skills in JavaScript, React/MERN stack, and am actively gaining proficiency in Java/Spring. I'm also pursuing a Bachelor in Computer Science (year 2).

My Product Management background equips me with strong UX design skills and a deep understanding of the intersection between user. business, and technical needs.

I'm eager to bring my unique blend of skills to a dynamic team where I can learn, grow and make meaningful contributions as a Software Engineer. I know that with the right opportunity, I can grow into a valuable asset and make a big impact to both the team and our customers.

EXPERIENCE

Full Stack Engineer Program

JUN 2024 - PRESENT

Nology

Nology is an intensive 12-week training program aimed at building strong practical Software Engineering skills. I completed over 6 personal projects and contributed to a student performance tracking tool that Nology is building for internal use. Tech Stack includes Typescript, MySQL, NestJS, React, Java, AWS, Jest and React Testing Library.

Software Engineer Intern

MAR - JUN 2024

Posi is a B2B SaaS Marketing product where I undertook a part-time internship along side a senior engineer as they launched this early stage side-project.

Over the course of 3 months I designed and implemented the user onboarding workflow using Typescript and React, added styling for user reports using Bulma and BEM and took initiative to resolve various UI bugs found in the existing code base.

Full Stack Engineer Trainee

SEP 2023 - MAR 2024

Coder Academy

Coder Academy is a 6-month long intensive, accredited coding bootcamp focussed on Full Stack development and Computer Science fundamentals. Tech stack includes Javascript, React, Python, Flask, Node.js, MongoDB, SQL, PostgreSQL. I also gained foundational skills in Relational Database design (normalisation), Time-Space Complexity (Big O) and Test Driven Development (TDD).

Co-Founder

JAN - JUN 2023

Talk to Maple

Accepted into Antler Australia's startup accelerator program and launched a gamified self-care mobile application using Flutterflow (frontend) and Xano (backend), gaining over 200 user downloads across apple and android app stores

Integrated with openAl's chatGPT Turbo 3.5 API and implemented Firebase authentication (including google sign in) which involved a user Migration from Xano to Firestore for improved data safety.

Product Manager

2022 - 2023

Culture Amp

Culture Amp is a B2B SaaS Product, helping companies build a better world of work. I was a Product Manager for their Performance Management product where I collaborated closely with development teams to deliver on a high impact product roadmap resulting in a 5% decrease in user churn over a 6-month period.

SKILLS

Languages

- Javascript / Typescript
- Java
- SQL

Frontend

- React
- React Testing Library
- Jest
- Next.js
- HTML / CSS
- Sass / SCSS

Backend

- Node.js
- Express.js
- Spring Boot
- MySQL
- PostgreSQL

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Computer Science

Deakin University
JUL 2024 - Present

Diploma of Information Technology

Coder Academy / AIT SEP 2023 - MAR 2024

UX UI Design Bootcamp

Academy Xi MAR - SEP 2021

EXPERIENCE CONT.

Product Manager

2021 - 2022

Surreal

Surreal is a B2B SaaS Event Management System, helping Venues better manage their live entertainment. As the company's first Product Manager I created and presented the international product strategy to investors, which was instrumental in securing an additional \$750,000 in VC funding.

Driving the product vision and collaborating closely with the CTO and development team, I ensured Surreal's new product was successfully launched into their first international market (UK), receiving positive signals from early adopters.

Product Manager

2019 - 2021

Henry Schein One

Henry Schein One is Australia's largest Dental Practice Management Software Provider. As Product Manager I uplifted customer NPS by 30 points and doubled user growth over a 12 month period through curation and execution of an impactful user-centric product roadmap.

Senior Technical Software Support

2017 - 2019

Henry Schein One

Handled all 2nd and 3rd level technical escalations including server migrations, managing system outages and writing, testing and running custom SQL scripts. Consistently provided excellent customer service and maintained a 99.9% customer satisfaction score.

PROJECTS

Sproutly Forum

GitHub Live Link

A full stack app built using MongoDB, Express.js, Node.js & React. Includes image storage, JWT authorisation and unit testing.

Google Books Search

<u>GitHub</u> <u>Liv</u>

Live Link

A full responsive frontend React SPA application powered by the Google Books API, Vite and Sass.

Techie Trinkets E-Shop

<u>GitHub</u>

<u>Live Link</u>

An e-commerce React application developed using React-Router for client-side routing and a Firestore database.